Vignesh Natarajan (VIGI)

Web App Developer // Node / React / Ruby / Rails

SUMMARY

My passion is to be part of the digital future and use my creativity to build tools that make a difference. Learning to programming has been the most satisfying experience of my career thus far, and with an accounting and entrepreneurial background spanning over 10 years I have a unique skill set in working as an employee and also as a business owner.

I am very excited about blockchain technology and would like to explore the possibility of working in that discipline in the future.

KEY SKILLS & COMPETENCIES

WEB DEVELOPMENT & DESIGN

- Ability to break a problem into small pieces
- Back end technologies Ruby on Rails, NodeJS, ExpressJS, SQL, MongoDB, Firebase
- Front end technologies React/S, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap
- Experience in working with Amazon S3 bucket, deploying to heroku and now.sh
- Experience in conceptualising and programming a web app by drawing out wireframes, planning database schema designs, preparing user flow diagrams and code documentation

SMALL BUSINESS - START UP, DEVELOPMENT & MANAGEMENT

- Extensive hospitality experience in all aspects of business management
- Operations and business development of both customer and business facing entities
- Driving a strong social media presence
- Ability to build and sell a profitable business

ACCOUNTING & FINANCE

- Strong analytical skills with an interest in statistics and economics
- In depth understanding of the financial year life cycle
- Ability to prepare, analyse and audit financial documents

WORK HISTORY

Sept 2017 -Dec 2017

Restaurant Manager

Mama's Buoi group of restaurants

Mama's Buoi is a trendy Vietnamese restaurant chain owned by the Roll'd Australia group. I worked here as a restaurant manager for 3 months prior starting to my programming course.

- Oversaw the launch of Mama's Buoi flagship store in the Chadstone dining precinct
- Managed every aspect of operations in front of house, bar and financial reporting
- Underwent a 2 week manager training program after which I recruited and trained a over
- Assisted with the set up of supplier accounts and negotiations

2016

Dec 2010 - Aug Founder/Owner/Operator/Financial Manager

RDV Holdings Pty Ltd, Adelaide, Australia

CHOCOLATREE | December 2010 - August 2016

With a turnover of over \$1.5 Million Chocolatree is an award winning market leader in the dessert cafe industry

SWEET AS BAKERY PATISSERIE | September 2013 - August 2016

Sweet as Bakery specialises in preparation and wholesale supply of Petit Gateaux, Cakes and handmade chocolates to local Adelaide cafes

HOLY GUACAMOLY/POCO PICANTE | December 2013 - October 2015

A successful Mexican Quick Service Restaurant providing fresh, exciting and quick food

COFFYLOSOPHY | March 2014 - March 2015

A very popular boutique café specialising in house brewed coffee, breakfast, brunch and lunch

Born March 1, 1985



Melbourne, Australia

Q 0431 602 005

☑ vigneshnataraj@gmail.com

in au.linkedin.com/in/vnatarajan85

O ifollowedthewhiterabbit.github.io

< CODE >

github.com/ifollowedthewhiterabbit

#SOCIALMEDIA

@vigi85 || twitter.com/vigi85

instagram.com/vig_eee

EDUCATION

Diploma in IT

Feb 2017-current Coder Academy

Melbourne, Australia

SKILLED IN

- Ruby
- Rails
- React JS
- Node IS HTML5
- C553
- SQL & NoSQL

Master of Business (Accounting)

2005 - 2007 University of South Australia

Adelaide, Australia

KEY SUBJECTS

- Financial accounting
- Commercial & corporate law
- Taxation law
- Management accounting
- Business ethics

Business set up

- Conceptualised and built 4 businesses from scratch
- Worked on store design (look and feel), designed logos, menus and pricing strategy
- Acquired and adhered to all necessary government and council approvals and requirements

Multi-store operations

- Managed operations and financials and all other aspects of four high volume stores
- Designed and implemented work procedures for all staff to maintain uniformity

B2B sales and customer relations

- Actively sourced new sales leads and cafes to sell petit gateaux, entremets, waffles and other baked good manufactured at our kitchen
- Maintaining and growing relationships with existing clients through regular meetings to keep them up to date with our product line

Sales increase and growth

- Achieved 8-10% year to year sales growth through strategic social media presence, print marketing, innovation, quality control and customer relations
- Starting in house production of cakes and chocolates, eventually leading to a 100% self produced menu which was executed at a low price point

Team building, leadership & mentoring

- Motivated managed and built a team of over 40 skilled and unskilled employees across
- Experienced in bringing out the best in staff and maintained an extremely low attrition

Vendor relationships

- Timely interaction with third party vendors from senior management to sales representatives
- Time to time negotiation of prices in ccordance according to purchasing power and need

Budgeting and cost control

- Setting comprehensive monthly budgets for marketing, advertising, staffing and cost of sales while maintaining a positive cash flow
- Forecasting monthly sales according to varying factors such as past sales, holiday season and weather
- Accounting and financial reporting
- Managed all day to day book keeping aspects (MYOB), preparation and reconciliation of financials
- Preparation and lodgement of quarterly BAS and yearly tax returns

Quality control and assurance

• Maintaining standards, consistency of taste and visual appeal of food served

Customer relations/focus

• Emphasis on the philosophy that the customer is always right

Jan 2008 - Nov Junior Auditor /Assistant Accountant

Accounting & Business Consulting Pty Ltd, Adelaide, Australia

Accounting & business consulting is a mid size public practice based in Adelaide. I had secured a graduate position as a junior accountant and auditor after my masters degree.

- Administered new and existing accounts in the Practice Manager software program by invoicing, maintaining, preparation of end of year financial accounts and PAYG statements for clients
- Preparing and lodging quarterly BAS for clients
- Assisted senior accountants in various trust account audits

May 2007 - Jan Administration Assistant

2008 Mentor Consultancy, Adelaide, Australia

> Mentor consultancy is an education consultancy firm originally based in Coimbatore, India. A temporary office was set up to assist international students coming into Adelaide to

- Processing paper work relating to admission of international students in Australia
- Organising accommodation and airport pick ups for incoming international students

study

Bachelor of Business (Management)

2002 - 2005 Bharathiyar University

Coimbatore, India

KEY SUBJECTS

- Marketing
- Economics
- Accounting principles
- International trade
- Analytics in management

ACHIEVEMENTS & CONTRIBUTIONS

- Successfully set up 4 businesses within 6 years
- Successfully sold all businesses on profit
- Won multiple accreditions for chocolate making in the Royal Adelaide and Melbourne food awards
- Maintained a negligible attrition rate in all businesses
- Set up a chocolate kiosk at Westfield Marion over Christmas periods
- Chocolatree has been also been part of the Adelaide fringe festival as a vendor
- Supported the local community by funding/sponsoring important social causes
- Completed BUPA challenge(long distance cycling) 3 years in a row
- Awarded certificate of recognition at University of South Australia for taking part in work placement scheme
- Played cricket at school, University & club levels

REFERENCES

Available upon request

Sep 2005 -May 2007

2010

Held various positions in customer service/retail/hospitality while pursuing full time